sen.com.au 2014-06-28

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to the collection of personal information ("PI") by or on behalf of Pacific Star Network Limited and all related companies ("Pacific Star"). References in this Privacy Policy to “SEN”,“MyMp” “Inside Football” “us”, “we” or “our” mean Pacific Star Network Limited of 473-479 Swan St, Richmond, Victoria, 3121 and its related companies.

We are committed to the protection of your PI and meeting the standards set out in the Privacy Act 1988 (Commonwealth) ("the Act") and the National Privacy Principles ("NPPs"). This policy sets out how we manage your PI and the rights and obligations that we both have in relation to that information.

We may from time to time, review and update this policy, including to take account of new and amended laws, new technology and or changes in our operation. All personal information will be governed by the most recently updated policy. There may also be specific instances of promotions or events that utilise a specific privacy policy, and in such circumstances notice of that policy will be provided and that policy shall take precedence over this policy in the event of any inconsistency between the two.

This policy was last updated on 20 January 2013.

Pacific Star gathers information for a number of commercial and operational purposes, enabling us to improve the nature of the services we provide and to facilitate your interaction with us.

 **1\. COLLECTION OF INFORMATION**

 **a. What Information We Collect**

In general the personal information we collect about you includes (but is not limited to) your name, contact details (phone numbers, email address, postal address) and in appropriate circumstances financial information such as credit card details if necessary to facilitate a financial transaction with you.

 **b. Why We Collect Personal Information**

We collect your PI to provide you with products and services and to administer our relationship with you. We also collect PI for marketing purposes and to provide you with information about special events, products and services (both our own and those of other companies) that may be of interest to you. We may state a more specific purpose at the time we collect your information at our discretion. Without this information being collected we may not be able to provide you with our products and services.

 **c. How We Collect Personal Information**

We primarily collect PI directly from you through written, electronic and/or verbal means of communication when you interact with us including, but not limited to:

(i) you participate in talkback discussions or programs;

(ii) you submit an entry into a competition or trade promotion;

(iii) you participate in listener loyalty programs;

(iv) you send us an email, SMS message or post an entry on any of our websites;

(v) you purchase products from us by credit cards or otherwise.

Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, we may collect your personal information when you request or acquire a product or service from us, register with us as a member, provide a product or service to us, complete a survey or questionnaire, enter a competition or event, contribute or participate in a fundraising, social or sporting event, participate in our services (including our radio programs, listener surveys, polls, blogs, forums or SMS or text message platforms or when you communicate with us through any other means, including listener feedback, complaints or in relation to any customer service activity.

We may also obtain details about you from marketing databases or other sources that are publicly available such as websites, journals, directories, mailing lists and phone books. We will only collect information about you from third parties in circumstances where your permission could reasonably be implied. If we do collect PI in this manner, we will endeavour to make you aware of who we are, the fact and manner of collection of this information and this Privacy Policy. If your information is provided by a third party we will ask the third party to tell you that they have provided us with your PI and provide you with a copy of this Privacy Policy.

We may also collect anonymous information through the use of cookies on our website. Cookies are pieces of information that are stored on your computer's hard disk. Most web-browsers are set to accept cookies but you can set your web-browser to refuse cookies. Cookies themselves do not identify users personally but they do allow the tracking of an individual's use of a website (including the IP address). You can configure your web browser to reject or accept cookies. If you reject cookies you may not be able to interact with us online. We generally use this information to report statistics, analyse trends, administer our services, diagnose problems and to improve the quality of our products and services. To the extent that this information does not constitute personal information, the National Privacy Principles do not apply and we may use this information for any purpose and by any means we choose in our sole discretion.

If at any time you provide personal or other information about someone other than yourself, you warrant that you have that person’s consent to provide such information for the purpose specified.

 **2\. USE AND DISCLOSURE**

 **a. Use**

By submitting your PI to us you consent to us using your PI in the following ways and for the following purposes:

(i) to provide you with our products or services including but not limited to your participation in our broadcast;

(ii) to administer our relationship with you, including but not limited to verifying your identity;

(iii) to facilitate the running of and your participation in trade promotions and other competitions;

(iv) to facilitate the running of and your participation in listener loyalty programs;

(v) to monitor activity on our websites, for the purpose of maintaining the security of those websites;

(vi) to compile listener databases and profiles to enable us to market goods and services more accurately;

(vii) for internal administrative purposes, such as procedural assessments, risk management, staff training, accounting, billing, product and service reviews; and

(viii) to identify and inform you about other products or services that may be of interest to you;

(ix) to market, improve and add to our products and services including our websites and our radio broadcasts;

(x) where there is a serious threat to an individual's life or to public health or safety;

(xi) to investigate any complaints about or made by you;

(xii) where there is reason to suspect unlawful activity has been engaged in;

(xiii) where required or authorised by law; or

(xiv) where required by an enforcement body.

If you do not wish to receive marketing or other communications from us, please contact us on the details below so that we can update your preferences.

If you provide us with your mobile telephone number, email address, IM address or other such personal information, you authorise us to send you promotional messages related to our products and services and the products and services that we promote. Such messages will be accompanied by a functional unsubscribe facility.

 **b. Disclosure**

We may disclose PI with Pacific Star affiliates and our related companies (in accordance with this Privacy Policy).

We may also provide PI to third parties:

(i) engaged by us to provide functions or provide products or services on our behalf such as storing and managing databases, processing credit card information, mailouts, debt collection, marketing research and advertising;

(ii) that are our agents, business partners or joint venture entities or partners;

(iii) that sponsor or promote any competition that we promote or conduct through our services; or

(iv) authorised by you to receive PI held by us.

These third parties do not have permission to use, sell or transfer personal information in any way.

We may also disclose PI to unrelated third parties (for example, our professional advisers and government authorities or agencies) where that disclosure is reasonably required to obtain advice, prepare legal proceedings, investigate suspected improper conduct or wrong doing, to assist a lawful authority in the discharge of its duties and/or by law.

Where we hold promotions in conjunction with other companies, we will offer you the opportunity to be contacted by our promotions partner. We will not provide your PI to the promotions partner unless you have opted in to having such PI passed on.

We cannot be held responsible for any misuse or unauthorised disclosure of your PI by these third parties. We generally advise you not to publish or communicate personal information, or at least to limit the personal information that you publish or communicate, to the public via our services, platforms or interactive forums. You acknowledge that by disclosing personal information on those services, platforms and interactive forums you are accepting that we cannot control any third party collection of that information.

 **3\. DATA QUALITY**

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the PI we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date. If your PI is incorrect or changes, please contact us on the details below so that we can update your PI and continue providing you with our services.

 **4\. DATA SECURITY**

Your PI is stored in a number of secure computer storage facilities and paper based files, and in other records. We have taken precautions to ensure that your PI is protected from misuse, loss and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

Once we no longer need your PI, we take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify your PI.

 **5\. INFORMATION REGARDING THIS POLICY**

If you have any questions whatsoever on our handling of your PI or the kind of PI we hold about you please contact us on the details below and we will endeavour to assist you with your request.

 **6\. ACCESS AND CORRECTION**

You generally have the right to access your personal information and we will provide you with a copy of any personal information we hold on request. The NPPs set out some circumstances in which we are not required to provide you with such access. If you ask for your PI and any of these circumstances apply, we may, if reasonable, agree with you on an intermediary which would allow sufficient access to your PI to meet your needs.

We may charge a fee for retrieving PI, in which case we will inform you of the fee in advance of providing the information.

 **7\. IDENTIFIERS**

As required by the NPPs, we do not collect or use Commonwealth government identifiers when interacting with you.

 **8\. ANONYMITY**

Where practical, you may deal with us on an anonymous basis. In some instances, because of the services we provide, if you do not provide us with your PI we may not be able to provide you with the requested product or service (for example, if we require your details in connection with a competition we are running, we cannot provide you with a prize should you be a prize winner and we cannot contact you).

 **9\. SENSITIVE INFORMATION**

Sensitive information includes information about your race or ethnic origins, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, or details of health, disability or sexual activity or orientation. We rarely ask for sensitive information, but may do so occasionally, for example, as part of a competition, promotion or survey. We will not require you to provide sensitive information unless:

(a) you have consented to providing such information (such consent will be deemed when you submit such information to us); or

(b) the collection of the information is specifically authorised or required by law.

 **10\. OPTING IN AND OUT**

At the point we collect information from you, you may be asked to ‘opt-in’, that is, to provide your consent to us using or disclosing your personal information other than in accordance with this policy or any applicable law. You will generally be given the opportunity to ‘opt out’ from communications to you in accordance with this policy.

If you receive communications purporting to be connected with us or our services that you believe have been sent to you other than in accordance with this policy, or in breach of any law, please write to us at the address set out below.

 **11\. CONTACT US**

If you have any queries about this Privacy Policy, please contact Pacific Star's Privacy Officer by mail at 473-479 Swan St, Richmond, Victoria, 3121.
